Guide to the Roger Wellington Tubby papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Roger Wellington Tubby papers
1923-1991
MS 508
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
16.75
(24 boxes)
The Roger W. Tubby Papers consist of voluminous personal diaries, as well as correspondence, writings, photographs, press releases, and newspaper clippings, ranging over the period 1925-83. The papers are largely unprocessed.
Tubby, Roger Wellington
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were donated to the Yale Library by Mr. Tubby, beginning in 1955.
Conditions Governing Access
The papers are closed to researchers until January 1, 2050.
Biographical / Historical
Roger Wellington Tubby, a government official and educator, was born in Greenwich, Connecticut, December 30, 1910, the son of George Prentiss and Frances Reynolds (Kidder) Tubby. He graduated from Choate School in 1929, and from Yale University in 1933, and undertook postgraduate studies at the Yale Law School and the London School of Economics. From 1938 to 1942 he worked for the Bennington (Vermont) Banner, first as a reporter and later as mariaging editor. During the war he served as an information specialist for the Board of Economic Warfare, and as director of information for the Foreign Economic Administration. He was director of information for the Office of International Trade, Department of Commerce, from 1945 to 1946; and press officer for the Department of State from 1945 to 1949. After this he served at the White House, becoming press secretary to the President for a short period in 1952. In 1956 he served as a personal assistant to the Democratic presidential candidate. From 1959 to 1961 he taught at Paul Smith's College in New York. During the 1960s he was assistant secretary for public affairs for the Department of State, and also served in Geneva as ambassador and as the United States representative to several international agencies, including the European office of the United Nations. From 1969 to 1972 he worked at the Foreign Service Institute, becoming dean of academic relations; after this he returned to Paul Smith's College as director of development. From 1975 to 1977 he was deputy commissioner of operations and planning for the New York State Department of Parks and Recreation. After this he was an adjunct professor at Plattsburgh State University, New York.
In 1936 he married Anne Williams. They had four children. Tubby died on January 4, 1991.
from Who's Who in America, 42nd edition, 1982-83, p.3374.
Scope and Contents
The Roger W. Tubby Papers consist of voluminous personal diaries, as well as correspondence, writings, photographs, press releases, and newspaper clippings, ranging over the period 1925-83. The papers are largely unprocessed.
- Inventory
  - 1923-1970 (Box 1–4)
  - 1971 May (Box 5)
  - 1971 October (Box 6–7)
  - 1973 June (Box 8–10)
  - 1975 April (Box 11)
  - 1976 Aug; 1977 July (Box 12)
  - 1978 May; 1979 Feb, Oct; 1980 January (Box 13)
  - 1981 January (Box 14)
  - 1982 July (Box 15)
  - 1984 April (Box 16)
- Additional material, 1932-1988; Accession 1989-M-037
  - Journals
    General
    All journals are interspersed with correspondence, clippings, photographs, etc.
    - 1984 January 1-September 18 (Box 1)
    - 1984 September 25-1985 August 18 (Box 1)
    - 1985 August 28-1986 July 13 (Box 1)
    - 1986 July 16-1987 January 29 (Box 1)
    - 1987 January 29-1988 January 6 (Box 1)
    - 1988 January 3-November 7 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence about starting a new four-year liberal arts college at Saranac Lake, New York, Circa 1955 (Box 2)
  - Oral history interview with Roger Tubby for the John F. Kennedy Library, by Joseph O'Connor, 1967 January 16 (Box 2)
  - Assorted clippings, letters, etc., Circa 1932-1988 (Box 2)
- Additional material, 1930-1989; Accession 1989-M-057
  - Correspondence, 1930s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Melinda, excerpts from a novel by Roger W. Tubby, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - New Bennington, excerpts from a novel by Roger W. Tubby ", Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Press clippings, 1960s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Photographs, 1988, undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional material, 1988-1989; Accession 1989-M-080
  - Journal (Correspondence, clippings, and photographs laid in.), 1988 November 17-1989 May 5 (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1989; Accession 1990-M-021
  - Journal, 1989 May 5-August 23 (Box 1)
    Correspondence, clippings, and photographs laid in.
- Additional material, 1989-1990; Accession 1991-M-002
  Scope and Contents
  Also includes Accession 1991-M-027
  - Journals
    (Journals are interspersed with correspondence, clippings, photographs, etc.)
    - 1989 September 1- 1990 January 31 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
    - 1990 January 31-June 27 (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Videotape interview with Roger W. Tubby, 1989 November (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Journal, 1990 June 6-September 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Additional material, Accession 1991-M-061
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
- Additional material, 1990; Accession 1991-M-069
  - Journal, 1990 September 15-December 17 (Box 1)